[The Heir]
[Episode 22]
The Tribute Ink selection begins now.
Candidates, please enter the venue
in an orderly manner.
Please let me through.
Master Qi.
Zhengshen,
why don't you get in?
I'd rather stay outside.
Don't you want to watch your father fight
for the authority over the Tribute Ink?
But it's against the rules.
Against the rules?
When you're in there,
you just need to obey the rules inside.
Let's go.
Master Qi, it...
Just go.
[Rushi House]
[Tingmo Pavilion]
[Jiangu House]
The primary selection is complete.
The Scholar Ink by the Chen family,
The ancient lacquer-soot ink
by the Li family,
and the Ziji Dragon Light Ink
by the Tian family are admitted
to the finals!
-Bravo!
What kind of ink are you presenting?
The Chen family presents the Cloud Ink.
The Li family presents
the Origin Ink.
The Tian family presents
the Jin Zhangzong Round Scented Ink.
As expected,
they had another plan in reserve.
Examiners, please test the ink.
[Ink examiner, Mr. Fengzhou]
The Chen family must have made use of
the formulas of tung oil soot
and lacquer soot for the Cloud Ink.
The ink yields a dense black
with luminous clarity.
In particular, the light ink areas
display distinct layers.
Each tone holds its place perfectly
without bleeding.
It is excellent.
Gentlemen,
what do you think of the ink
presented by the Tian family?
The Round Scented Ink truly
lives up to its reputation.
It's aromatic but not overwhelming,
so it helps to calm the mind
when one writes or paints.
It performs even better
as it's applied to paper.
The ink takes a deep and steady tone,
yet never feels heavy or stifling—
rich but not sluggish.
It's of premium quality.
The Origin Ink is a continuation
of the Li family's
best pine soot ink formula.
Needless to say,
this is fine piece of ink.
However,
pardon me for being inadequate,
as I really cannot find
anything special about it.
The pigment
is indeed more delicate and translucent.
But it only reflects ordinary progress
in materials and techniques.
The best of pine soot is not brought out.
This ink can barely hold a candle to that
presented by the Tian and Chen families.
The two ink examiners of you
are both leading figures
in the literary and art circles.
You made a fair judgement.
Li Ink...
accepts it wholeheartedly.
The Li family's ink is rated as grade one.
-Bravo!
Bravo!
The Tian family's ink
is rated as supreme grade.
-Bravo!
The Tian family's ink
is also rated as supreme grade.
-Bravo!
[Li's Ancestral Hall]
Here they come.
Zhen.
Eldest Aunt.
I figured Eighth Uncle would be reluctant
to come to the ancestral hall.
So I arranged the items you asked for
right here.
Does this seem alright to you?
How very thoughtful of you, Eldest Aunt.
Is my grandfather not here yet?
He is arriving.
-Eighth Master Li.
The auspicious hour is upon us.
Let's begin.
I, Li Zhen, master of Li Ink, have brought
all members of the clan to pay respects
to the Li ancestors.
In today's Tribute Ink selection,
the Origin Ink we presented was rated
as grade one.
It will be now offered here
by its maker, Li Jingdong.
This unworthy descendant Li Jingdong
is a poorly educated man
of mediocracy.
Despite years of learning,
my skills are still inadequate.
For the first time, I entered my creation
into the Tribute Ink Selection.
Yet I failed and returned
in defeat.
I, Jingdong,
has let down Li Ink
and my late father.
Deeply ashamed of myself,
I'm feeling utterly disgraced.
Uncle Jingdong.
Please get up, Uncle Jingdong. Come on.
Get up now.
Grandfather.
When you attended
the Tribute Ink selection
with the Sixth and Seventh Grandfathers
for the first time,
what grade was your ink rated?
Our ink couldn't even reach
grade one in our first competition.
Uncle Jingdong,
your ink was rated as grade one
in your first Tribute Ink selection.
You're starting from a better place
than my grandfather and his brothers.
When Li Ink was in grave trouble,
you bravely assumed
all challenging responsibilities.
Li Ink
is proud of you.
Please get up.
Father.
Everyone, do you know
why I named this ink
the Origin Ink?
It stems from "Yuan," one of
the four virtues of the Qian hexagram.
It stands for a new start
after an ending.
The Tribute Ink case 13 years ago still
aches the heart of everyone present here.
Li Ink plummeted to the bottom due to it.
But now, the Origin Ink
has brought upon us a fresh start.
The Li family entered the Origin Ink
into the just finished
Tribute Ink selection
exactly because this ink
is the result of every Li member's
hard work.
Nothing but the Origin Ink
can stop our hearts from aching again.
I firmly believe
that as long as we make concerted efforts,
Li Ink will regain its glory one day.
The creation of the Origin Ink
is attributed to all of us.
Li Ink couldn't have gained a new start
without everyone present.
Hereby, I, Li Zhen, extend
sincere gratitude to all of you.
What exactly is going on?
The sun is about to set,
but there isn't a result yet.
-That's right.
-Right.
The selection is taking so long.
Everyone,
it's getting late.
There must be a result for every match.
Tian Ink and Chen Ink—
which deserves to be the Tribute Ink?
Judges, please share your thoughts.
The Round Scented Ink is invaluable,
making it more suited for the Tribute Ink.
I beg to differ.
Tian Ink is too dry.
It is obviously newly made
and needs more time to settle.
In terms of quality,
Chen Ink is certainly better.
Got it.
In this case,
I announce
that the winner
of the Tribute Ink selection is...
Here comes the royal preceptor,
Sage Qing He.
Greetings, respectable sage.
Dispense with the formalities, everyone.
I can't believe
your sudden visit to Huizhou
was completely unknown to me, dear sage.
I deserve severe punishment for it.
While passing by this place,
the sage heard
the winner of the Tribute Ink selection
couldn't be decided after a long time,
so he specially came in
to provide support.
The timing is impeccable, Sage Qing He.
In this Tribute Ink selection,
the Tian and Chen families have presented
nearly equally premier ink products.
Sage, as a companion
to His Majesty for long,
you are highly accomplished
in calligraphy.
Hereby, I boldly invite you
to assess the ink.
Oh you.
You could never handle tasks well
back when you worked
in the imperial palace.
Fine then.
I'll help you with the selection.
Thank you, Sage.
Sage Qing He,
this is Tian Ink.
This is Chen Ink.
Why is there a fly?
This ink is unclean.
The fragrance of Styrax resin.
His Majesty will like it.
In my opinion,
the Tribute Ink
should be Tian Ink.
Sage Qing He,
please take one more look at Chen Ink.
It truly is a fine piece of ink.
Sage, we beg you to check it again.
Sage,
we implore you to reassess Chen Ink.
Sage, we cordially ask you
to make a just decision!
Now that you have given an instruction,
Sage,
I completely agree with your opinion.
Thank you, Sage Qing He.
Thank you, Lord Yan.
The Tian family promises
to meet expectations, produce enough ink,
and deliver it to His Majesty
as soon as possible.
[Zhenbao House] [Chen]
Father.
Father!
Help!
[Literary Association]
[Champion of Ink Making]
Champion of Ink Making.
Champion of Ink Making!
We are the champion of ink making!
From now on,
the Tian family will be marching towards
great prosperity and huge success!
Benchang.
Quickly have
this plaque hung up in our ink workshop.
My love,
prepare a banquet soon.
It's a convention in Hui Ink
for the Ink Affairs Official
to attend a banquet held by the winner
of the Tribute Ink selection.
Do take the matter seriously.
Don't worry, Master.
All is properly arranged.
Really?
The food and wine must be vegetarian.
Because Sage Qing He will attend it too.
Ronghua,
your two brothers have told me
about what happened
in the Literary Association just now.
You are a significant contributor
to the Tian family.
Let's get in.
Ronghua,
take a seat.
No, wait.
Ronghua, have some tea.
Let me serve it.
Ronghua,
have some tea.
Father and I submitted visiting cards
for several times in the Capital,
seeking an audience with Sage Qing He.
Yet he never agreed to meet us.
How did you make his acquaintance?
Yes, dear sister.
It's said that the sage can even enter
and leave the imperial palace freely.
What an unusual figure.
He has been friends with the Xu family
for a long time.
It was not difficult for me
to meet his acquaintance.
Oh right.
The sage told my fortune
when he first saw me.
He said
that the family I was born into
refused to nurture me.
I am destined to receive little affection
from my own family.
Father,
Mother,
am I right?
Yes, yes.
Ronghua,
we had no choice but to treat you
like that in the past.
We're sorry to have upset you.
If you are not having a good time
in the Xu family,
how about I go and beg Mrs. Hu
to let you come home to us?
Mother,
do you think the Xu family would allow one
to come and go as one pleases?
Although Sage Qing He has made a decision,
it cannot quell the dispute in Huizhou.
Benchang,
you are now in charge of the family.
You are perfectly aware of how this plaque
was attained.
From now on,
please focus on nothing but ink.
First, no mistakes in the important task
of delivering ink to the Capital.
Second, try to be diligent, serious,
and respectful
as you solidify
the foundation of Tian Ink.
Only in this way can the Tian family
enjoy long-term prosperity.
I will keep that in mind.
Little did I expect...
the Tribute Ink selection to end this way.
All my planning over these days
became in vain
as Sage Qing He lightly swept
his whisk.
This time, after returning to Huizhou,
although I've brought down Zhao Shen,
the Tian family has thrived
by using their victory
in the Tribute Ink selection.
Meanwhile, for failing to raise
a military fund of ten thousand taels,
I'll be severely punished by the general.
Now, I am not only going to lose
my position as the master of Yihousheng,
but also
my military post.
That said, Father,
Aunt,
Brother,
I will not give up
until I brush off the dirt
thrown onto your names.
Master.
Is everything ready?
Bills, documents,
and all the ready silver in the account
have been sorted out.
Master, without Yihousheng
and your military post,
what are we going to fight
the Tian family with?
I should've handled this matter
in a better way.
Let's pay a visit to Sister first.
Take this.
It didn't occur to me
even the Chen family would lose.
Despite all the hustle these days,
you still lost your position.
Master.
Wait for me outside.
This is all the ready silver
in Yihousheng's account.
Fifteen hundred taels in total.
These are all the bills of my investments
in the ink industry using military funds
since I arrived in Huizhou,
including contracts
with the Li Ink Workshop
and details of dividends
from the ancient lacquer-soot ink.
Oh, right.
The most valuable thing right now
should be this contract
with the New Li Ink Workshop.
It is an agreement
on splitting dividends from Fu Jin Ink.
All of these contracts add up to about
2,500 taels.
The total dividends in two or three months
should be around 2,000 taels.
Altogether, the value is 6,000 taels.
As for the 1,000 taels
invested in the Chen family,
I suppose it'll double in profit.
You've settled everything
about Yihousheng.
Then what about you? What's your plan?
I haven't figured it out yet.
Listen,
the Tian family is at its peak now.
You cannot take any risks.
The Tian family is at its peak...
Don't worry, Sister.
I won't take any risks.
Even if I don't think about myself,
I'll have to think about Marshal Qi.
I am deeply indebted to him.
How can I ever implicate him
for my own interests?
Since there's nothing left
for you at this place,
why not go back to Marshal Qi
and seek a fresh start?
At this point,
how can I show my face
in front of Marshal Qi?
Although I haven't figured out a plan,
I won't leave Huizhou anyway.
I'm not going anywhere.
Then how about this?
I'll ask Zhen for a favor.
Sister.
She could help you settle.
Sister!
Please be seated, Sister.
It's my own business to figure out
a way to in Huizhou.
Since it's my personal matter,
I'd like to keep Zhen out of it.
I'd hate to get her in any danger.
So, if you still see me as a brother,
Sister, please
don't go ask Zhen for help,
or bring this matter up again.
You seem to be in a good mood, Master Qi.
Zhen,
since you took over Li Ink,
you've been busy with work.
How did you find time to come here?
Just like you,
I need my own leisure time
every now and then.
I have a bit more of that than you do.
I have been idling the entire day.
It seems...
my sister has talked to you.
She's only looking out for you.
As my grandfather once said,
life is all about ups and downs.
Everyone's fortune differs.
A temporary setback means nothing.
Take me as an example.
I was expelled from the clan before,
but now I am in charge of Li Ink.
In my opinion,
as long as one has a bite to eat
and some strength left,
one can always achieve one's goals.
Thank you for comforting me, Zhen.
That said,
just pretend
you don't know about my difficulties.
How can I pretend not to know?
Part of the credit
of creating the Origin Ink goes to you.
I can't sit back and do nothing
when you're in adversity.
Besides,
you're a major shareholder of Li Ink.
If you don't mind,
come work in Li Ink with me.
I assure you
that as long as I'm around,
you'll have food to eat
and a place to stay.
Although I am down and out now,
I can still build something up
with my own hands.
So, making a living
won't be a problem for me.
You're not concerned
about your livelihood.
But what about your rumbling stomach?
It's a problem to solve, isn't it?
Fine. Let's have it sorted then.
In which restaurant?
Master Qi,
it's a simle home-cooked meal.
If there's anything inadequate,
please forgive us.
Eighth Master Li, how nice of you.
I took the liberty of calling on you
but you didn't turn me away.
I'm already deeply grateful.
Master Qi,
just make yourself at home.
Don't stand on ceremony.
Eat up.
Dig in.
Let's eat.
Zhengliang. Zhengliang!
Quick, bring a jar of wine over.
Some bowls, too!
Got it!
Here comes the chicken soup.
Here's the soup.
Fetch some bowls now.
I'll go get some, Mother.
Eat up.
Have some more.
Master Qi, you're a rare guest for us.
Make sure you have enough drinks
and enjoy them tonight.
Sure.
Come on, let me make a toast to you first.
Here.
Thank you, Auntie.
Alright, enough.
Do enjoy yourself.
You can really hold your liquor,
Master Qi.
Quick, fill Master Qi's bowl.
Let me help.
Mother, you're supposed
to entertain the guest,
not to get him drunk.
It's a good thing for him to get drunk,
so he could drown all his sorrows in wine.
Once you're drunk,
you'll forget everything bothering you!
Come on.
Let's all propose a toast to Master Qi.
Just be seated.
Eighth Master Li.
Come on.
Don't drink too much.
No, drink more.
Zhen,
I just learned to make this dish.
Have a try.
See if I've picked up
Mother's cooking skills.
Sure.
Let me try it.
As Zhen's elder brother,
how could you not let her try it first?
Seriously, you giant turnip,
don't you know to serve the guest first?
Here you are, Master Qi.
Try my sister-in-law's cooking.
Thank you, Zhen.
You're welcome.
Grandpa.
Mother, eat some more.
Thank you, Zhen.
Easy on the drink.
You giant turnip, help yourself.
We're with a guest. Stop calling me that.
Taste it now. See if it's good.
Sure.
I thought it was cooked by Mother.
Qiu'e has really got the essence
of my cooking.
Qiu'e's cooking is amazing.
I've never cared about rules,
but I still made Luo Ink into Tribute Ink.
You should be the same.
Ignore those family rules and principles.
Just do what you want with all your heart.
One day,
I will make Luo Ink
the best of Hui Ink.
If you really grow into a business
in the future,
then help me
open Luo Ink shops all over the world.
Deal?
Deal.
Have some more.
So tasty.
Scram before I change my mind!
Don't!
I'm leaving. Alright?
Let's go.
Eat up.
One more piece for you.
A toast to you, Eighth Master Li.
Auntie.
A toast to you too.
Sure.
Here.
Zhen.
Come on.
A toast to you.
A refill for you.
Thanks, Zhengliang.
Qiu'e, a toast to you as well.
Easy on the drink.
Zhengliang, a toast to you.
Alright. Don't gulp it.
I am very envious of Li Zhen
having a brother like you.
Nice and slow. You good?
Yes, I'm good.
Careful. Mind your steps!
Got it!
Let's go.
Where am I?
On the way home.
Let's go.
Home?
Be good and go with me.
No, I'm not going home.
My home is right here.
No, no, no.
Your home is not here.
My home is right here.
This isn't your home.
This is my home.
Listen, I have a brother at home.
As long as he's around...
I won't be deserted.
Sure, you won't be deserted.
Brother,
I'm heading to the second floor.
No, not the second floor!
Yes, just the second floor.
Please go with me.
You can't desert me...
I won't. I won't.
Zhen, how to deal with this?
I see you've woken up, Master Qi.
Zhen, yesterday,
I caused you so much trouble.
I'm so sorry.
Goodbye.
Where are you going?
To work.
To work where?
A shareholder has become
a long-term employee.
I'm heading to work
in the Li Ink Workshop.
Goodbye.
Pull the door inward.
[Misty Rain]
The ink workshop hasn't yielded
any profits these past few months.
We cannot afford to hire workers,
so we'll have to let our own
ink makers to repair the workshop.
I'm sorry for the terrible thing
I did to you and the Li family.
I shouldn't have set that fire and...
Forget about that, Uncle Jingdong.
It's all in the past now.
Let's not bring it up again.
Manager Shao,
when is the repair
scheduled to be completed?
In about half a year.
That won't do. It's too long.
It'll cause loss of regular clients
and reduce the morale of our employees.
Even the ink workshop
will have to be closed down.
We must figure out a way
to have the repair done quicker.
You want to sell
the Li family's farmlands?
In your dreams!
I'm not selling them, but mortgaging them.
The slow repair of the ink workshop
is entirely due to the lack of money.
Only by mortgaging the farmlands for cash
can we speed up the reconstruction
and resume production soon.
Sister-in-law, Jiangyue,
Zhen and I have discussed this idea.
Although it's a bit risky,
this is
the only feasible solution at present.
You two are really backing each other up.
The ink workshop surely matters.
But don't the lives of these many people
in the mansion also matter?
Sister-in-law,
please say something.
You know the family finances best.
The whole family's daily expenses
all depend on the revenue
of our farmlands and shops.
If they are mortgaged,
how are we going to live?
Jiangyue,
I understand your concerns.
But the ink workshop is in trouble now,
isn't it?
As you just heard,
this is the only feasible solution.
We women at home can't help with much.
The least we can do is tighten our belts
for a few days.
Things will get better.
Ever since I married into the Li family,
the foundation
of the household
has never been touched
in whatever adversity.
How come disasters have kept
befalling us and shortfalls worsening
after this girl's return?
I'm telling you,
I reject this plan!
Fourth Aunt,
once we sign new orders,
new cash flow will naturally follow.
At the latest, we'll redeem the farmlands
when the ink workshop is rebuilt.
Otherwise, if Li Ink really collapses,
though we can rely on the family's
farmlands and properties,
our lives
won't be much comfortable.
I've truly underestimated you, Li Zhen.
I thought you just
wanted to take over the ink workshop.
Little did I imagine
you could be this ruthless.
You're actually exploiting
the family's hardship
to drain all our wealth!
Jiangyue,
today,
all those who can decide for the Li family
are gathered here.
Since our opinions differ,
we should
let Wanyi have the final say
on this matter.
I agree with Zhen's proposal.
Then it's settled.
You already decided everything.
Why did you even ask me
to come discuss it?
You're all in cahoots
to drive the Li family to ruin!
[Changsheng Garden]
Master Tian,
what a magnificent manor
you have.
It is no inferior to the noble's houses
in the Capital.
Everything here
is unpresentable and vulgar.
The presence of you and Lord Yan here
has really
brought light to our humble dwelling.
Cheers, everyone.
Bingyou.
The ink industry in Huizhou is prosperous,
and the ink merchants wealthy.
It means that you're doing your job well
as the Ink Affairs Official.
When Ronghua and I deliver
the Tribute Ink to the Capital
and meet His Majesty,
we will surely report
your good work faithfully.
Thank you so much, Sage.
I feel utterly grateful.
Sage,
Ronghua hasn't been home for a long time.
She didn't get to spend much time
with our parents during this visit.
Please let her stay here
for a few more days.
I can deliver the ink to the Capital
in her stead.
How considerate of you, Benchang.
However, Aunt is urging me to go back.
I couldn't stay here even if I wanted to.
Since Benchang took charge of Tian Ink,
he's been handling everything personally
and working day and night.
All matters big and small
in the ink workshop
is taken care of by him alone.
On my way back to the Capital,
I can also deliver the Tribute Ink.
This way, Benchang,
you'll be spared
from an exhausting journey.
Ronghua,
I'm in charge of Tian Ink now.
The delivery is part of my duty.
We are with the sage,
a distinguished guest, right now.
Ronghua is busy with her stuff.
Why not let Benchang
deliver the ink instead?
That said,
Benchang has things to do
in the ink workshop.
How about this?
I've been the one
dealing with Tian Ink's clients.
I am also familiar with the Capital.
Why not let me deliver the ink this time?
Huizhou is truly a blessed land.
Everyone born and raised here is smart.
Benchang.
In my opinion,
your sister handles everything properly.
I think she should be the one delivering
the ink to the Capital.
Sure, Sage Qing He.
Bingyou.
I have a few more words to say
to the Tian family.
You may leave now.
Got it. I'll be leaving then.
Everything hinges on you now, Sage.
I will be awaiting good news.
Sage,
this is a small gift prepared for you.
Such rootless stuff is unclean.
Take it away now.
It's offending my sight.
Benchang,
the sage has devoted himself
to serving immortals.
His hands are not to sullied
with such lowly earthly things
handled by nameless nobodies.
Ronghua truly knows me well.
I heard the previous County Magistrate
of this place was just found guilty.
Your household
is in need of an accountant.
It's all because they touched things
they shouldn't have.
Tian Ink just won
the latest Tribute Ink selection,
Many eyes are on you lot now,
in secret or openly.
I was just about to remind you
of being cautious in every way
so as not to let anyone find anything
to hold against you
and slander me with.
Yes.
Sage, you're a noble being.
I shouldn't have been so rude.
[Styrax Ink]
Ronghua,
I cast a divination today.
The hexagram was very bad.
Sage,
should the ink be improved in any way?
This ink
is almost perfect.
But Styrax resin
is from Nanyang after all.
It's not a domestic product.
Writing ritual poems
for the Three Supreme Deities
is a bit inappropriate.
Then what should be done?
The ink used for ritual poems directly
connects us to immortals.
The best choice is surely
pine soot ink
made from century-old pine timber.
Top-grade pine soot ink is said to be
extremely precious
and even worth a thousand taels of gold
in the Capital.
But don't worry, Master Tian.
Everything on this precious land is great.
You can collect
top-grade pine timber locally
to produce pine soot ink,
with which I'll set up an altar
to pray for the people through rituals.
Sage, you may not know
that there's a serious outbreak
of pine wilt disease in Huizhou.
Let alone century-old pine timber,
even ordinary pine timber
is hard to find at this time.
Pine wilt disease?
Exactly.
To add to that, this disease is incurable.
Now many ink workshops in Huizhou
are using tung oil to make ink instead.
I think this is why
pine soot ink is so expensive
in the Capital.
No wonder the divination today
shows I lack the Wood element this year.
You lack the Wood element?
Sage,
how about
I accompany you to Mount Qiyun tomorrow?
There stands
a thousand-year-old ginkgo tree.
The leaves are turning gold at this time.
Maybe we can share its luck and longevity.
Sounds nice!
You're such a good child.
Great.
Great idea!